251 10th St. NW, C509 Atlanta, GA 30318 U.S.A.

ChangSeok Oh

Profile: https://shivamidow.github.io E-mail: changseok@gnome.org Mobile: +1 (404) 740-7896

Open source enthusiast and hacker specializing in web technology and linux-based systems. A WebKit and GNOME project contributor. More than 8 years experience at major players in the industry. Looking for opportunities in Web browser, Web Security & Privacy, Kernel, and Computer Graphics.

Skills

WebKit, Blink/Chromium, GNOME, Linux, C/C++, Python, HTML/CSS/Javascript, Objective-C, Java, OpenGL/OpenGL ES, Clutter, Computer Graphics, GTK+, eBPF, BCC, Ethereum, Git, OBS, Clang, LLVM, GStreamer, Tizen, Linux Perf, Bluetooth LE, ReactJS, React Native, Embedded system, Puppeteer

Education

08/2017 - present 08/2017 - 08/2019 03/2000 - 06/2008 Ph.D student (advisor: Prof. Wenke Lee) in Computer Science, Georgia Tech in Atlanta, GA, U.S.A. M.S. in Computer Science (Computer Systems, GPA: 3.87 / 4.0), Georgia Tech in Atlanta, GA, U.S.A. Dual B.E. in Digital Media and Computer Engineering, Ajou University, South Korea

Professional Experience

06/2019 - present Intern at Igalia, S.L. in A Coruña, Spain • Bring ANGLE backend for WebGL to WebKitGTK • Zero copy texture sharing between Mesa and ANGLE via Linux DMA buffer 05/2020 - 08/2020 Intern at Samsung Research America in Mountain View, CA 05/2019 - 08/2019 • Build a web app for health data analysis with ReactJS (frontend) and Node.js (backend) • Built an automated system that verifies UI of a watch app by using Tizen automation framework Profiled memory usage and revealed possible memory leak of a watch app by using Valgrind • Implemented file transfer via Bluetooth LE in an React Native watch application Software engineer at Collabora Ltd. in Cambridge, UK 08/2012 - 03/2016 • Developed hardware based compositing based on Clutter in WebKit • Resource efficient web browser based on GNOME Epiphany for Raspberry Pi 2+ • Customized WebKit features and API set for Smart TV Alliance SDK 07/2008 - 08/2012 Assistant Software engineer at Samsung Electronics in Suwon, South Korea • Developed an in-house web layout engine for Smart TVs, Printers in C++ • Implemented WebGL and Accelerated Compositing in WebKit EFL by using OpenGL ES for Tizen Intern at Samsung Software Membership in Suwon, South Korea 07/2007 - 06/2008 • Developed a 3D racing game using DirectX on Windows (video)

Academic Experience

08/2017 - 08/2019

Research assistant at School of Computer Science, Georgia Tech

- Redesign chromium to block user tracking with web browser fingerprints
- Debloat chrome browser with feature sunsetting on the fly by binary rewriting
- Developed a defense system against micro DDoS by profiling resources with HPC (Intel PCM, MBM)
- Implemented an idle profiler that diagnoses off-cpu time in multi-threaded program using HPC

08/2019 - present

Teaching assistant at School of Computer Science, Georgia Tech

• CS 6262: Network Security, Design and Implement the XSS task using node is and Chrome Extension

Open Source Projects

04/2013 - present

Committer at WebKit (patches)

- Implement Gamepad API with libmanette
- Implement AVIF image decoder with dav1d
- Implemented OpenGL ES backend for Accelerated Compositing.
- Developed memory pressure handler that copes with out-of-memory on top of Linux cgroup.
- Enhance WebGL support and Fix layout and rendering issues
- Fix CVE security bugs in WebKit (CVE-2020-10018, CVE-2020-11793)

10/2013 - present

Member at GNOME foundation (patches)

• Translate GNOME Web and its Help document in Korean

01/2015 - present

Contributor at Chromium/Blink (patches)

Implemented a CSS spec called font-size-adjust
Fix layout and rendering issues in blink

Publication

CCS 2020

Slimium: Debloating the Chromium Browser with Feature Subsetting

By Chenxiong Qian, HyungJoon Koo, ChangSeok Oh, Taesoo Kim, Wenke Lee

Patents

US 20110296323 US 20110289110 Web page management method and apparatus and storage medium thereof Method of re-searching webpage and apparatus and storage medium therefor US 20110093606 Interface method and display device Interface method and display device

Presentations

12/07/2014 Web Engines Hackfest 2014 in A Coruña, Spain (slides)
09/29/2014 DEVIEW 2014 in Seoul, South Korea (slides, video)
Jeju University in Jeju, South Korea (slides)
DevOn 2013 in Seoul, South Korea (slides)

Last update : 07/29/2020